Transcript and translation
from http://tinyurl.com/kz7ao92
Sung by Анна Бутурлина (Anna Buturlina)
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Метель укроет склоны горных вершин
Metel’ ukroet sklony gornyh veršin
The storm blankets tall mountain slopes,
not a footprint to be seen
И белым-бела земля.
I belym-bela zemlja.
and the white ground.
A kingdom of isolation,
Безмолвное королевство,
Bezmolvnoe korolevstvo,
A silent kingdom,
and it looks like I'm the queen
Королевой стала я.
Korolevoj stala ja.
and I have become its Queen.
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
А ветер стонет и на сердце ураган.
A veter stonet i na serdce uragan.
The wind moans on the hurricane of my heart,
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Мне б его сдержать, но я не могла.
Mne b ego sderžat’, no ja ne mogla.
I was supposed to keep it in, but I could not.
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Не открывай, храни секрет,
Ne otkryvaj, hrani sekret,
Don't open up, keep the secret,
Be the good girl you always had to be
Будь хорошей девочкой для всех.
Bud’ horošej devočkoj dlja vseh.
Be the good girl for everyone
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Закрой все чувства на замок,
Zakroj vse čuvstva na zamok,
Lock up all feelings in the castle,
Well, now they know!
Но тщетно всё!
No tŝetno vsë!
But in vain all!
Let it go, let it go!
Отпусти и забудь,
Otpusti i zabud’,
Let go and forget,
Can't hold it back any more!
Что прошло - уже не вернуть.
Čto prošlo - uže ne vernut’.
What has happened will not come back
Let it go, let it go!
Отпусти и забудь,
Otpusti i zabud’,
Let go and forget,
Turn away and slam the door!
Новый день укажет путь.
Novyj den’ ukažet put’.
The new day shows the path
I don't care what they're going to say
Не боюсь ничего уже,
Ne bojus’ ničego uže,
I'm not scared of anything now
Let the storm rage on
Пусть бушует шторм -
Pust’ bušuet štorm -
Let the storm go on
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Холод всегда мне был по душе.
Holod vsegda mne byl po duše.
I always liked the cold.
It's funny how some distance
А я бегу всё выше,
A ja begu vsë vyše,
I will run higher
Makes everything seem small
На ледяную гладь.
Na ledjanuju glad’.
On the icy surface
And the fears that once controlled me
И страхам дней минувших
I straham dnej minuvših
And the fears of yesterday
Can't get to me at all!
Меня уж не догнать.
Menja už ne dognat’.
Cannot catch up to me
It's time to see what I can do
Пора узнать, что я могу -
Pora uznat’, čto ja mogu -
It's time to know, what I can do
To test the limits and break through
На службу призову пургу,
Na službu prizovu purgu,
The blizzard is at my service
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Свободу обрету во льдах,
Svobodu obretu vo l’dah,
I shall find freedom in the ice
I'm free!
Навсегда!
Navsegda!
Forever!
Let it go, let it go!
Отпусти и забудь
Otpusti i zabud’
Let go and forget
I am one with the wind and sky
Этот мир из твоих грёз.
Ètot mir iz tvoih grëz.
This world is from your dreams
Let it go, let it go!
Отпусти и забудь,
Otpusti i zabud’,
Let go and forget
You'll never see me cry
И не будет больше слёз.
I ne budet bol’še slëz.
And there will be no more tears!
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Здесь мой дом, Мой снежный удел.
Zdes’ moj dom, Moj snežnyj udel.
Here's my home, My snowy destiny
Let the storm rage on...
Пусть бушует шторм...
Pust’ bušuet štorm...
Let the storm go on...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Искрится воздух И земля от моих чар.
Iskritsja vozduh I zemlja ot moih čar.
The air and the ground sparkle from my spells,
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Подвластны мне мороз и лёд, Ну что за дивный дар.
Podvlastny mne moroz i lëd, Nu čto za divnyj dar.
Subject to my ice and snow, what a wonderful gift!
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
И вот уже я знаю, как мне дальше быть!
I vot uže ja znaju, kak mne dal’še byt’!
And I already know, how I am supposed to be!
I'm never going back
Я не вернусь назад,
Ja ne vernus’ nazad,
I will not go back,
The past is in the past!
Должна я всё забыть.
Dolžna ja vsë zabyt’.
I must forget everything!
Let it go, let it go!
Отпусти и забудь!
Otpusti i zabud’!
Let go and forget!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
И на небо лети зарёй!
I na nebo leti zarëj!
And the rays of dawn fly through the sky!
Let it go, let it go!
Отпусти и забудь,
Otpusti i zabud’,
Let go and forget,
That perfect girl is gone
Полярный сияй звездой!
Poljarnyj sijaj zvezdoj!
The polar stars shine!
Here I stand in the light of day
Встречу я Первый свой рассвет.
Vstreču ja Pervyj svoj rassvet.
Meeting I, At his first dawn
Let the storm rage on!
Пусть бушует шторм -
Pust’ bušuet štorm -
Let the storm go on!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Холод всегда мне был по душе.
Holod vsegda mne byl po duše.
I always liked the cold.